beckvalleybooks.blogspot.com 2019-03-31

# Beck Valley Books & more: Privacy Policy

**Privacy Policy**

This is the privacy policy for Beck Valley Books; [www.beckvalleybooks.blogspot.com](http://www.beckvalleybooks.blogspot.com/) and provided by Sharon Martin. The purpose of this policy is to explain to you how we receive, collect use and protect your personal information while browsing or using this website, including your rights under current laws and regulations. If you do not agree to the following policy you may wish to cease viewing / using this website.

**Policy key definitions:**  
"I", "our", "us", or "we" refer to the business, [Beck Valley Books].  
"you", "the user" refer to the person(s) using this website.  
GDPR means General Data Protection Act.  
PECR means Privacy & Electronic Communications Regulation.  
ICO means Information Commissioner's Office.  
Cookies mean small files stored on a users computer or device.  
  
**_Data our website collects and how it is used_**  
**  
****Information you voluntarily submit to the website:**  
We may collect personal information from you such as your name or email address. For example, you may voluntarily submit information to the website by leaving a public comment, subscribing to a newsletter, or submitting a contact form. I will never sell or give away this information, nor will I ever sell or give away your e-mail address should you contact me.

**Automatically-Collected Information:**  
We automatically collect certain information about you and the device with which you access the website. For example, when you use the website, we will log your IP address, operating system type, browser type, referring website, pages you viewed, and the dates/times when you accessed the website. We may also collect information about actions you take when using the website, such as links clicked. We can not use the information gathered to identify and connect to you as a person.

**Cookies:**  
We may log information using cookies, which are small data files stored on your browser by the Website. We may use both session cookies, which expire when you close your browser, and persistent cookies, which stay on your browser until deleted, to provide you with a more personalized experience on the website.

**Third-party use of personal information:**  
We will not share your information with third parties unless you voluntarily submit information for that purpose or you explicitly authorize us to do so. Additionally, the website uses third-party service providers to service various aspects of the website. Each third-party service provider’s use of your personal information is dictated by their respective privacy policies. The website currently uses the following third-party service providers:

Google Analytics  
To track website usage and provide information such as referring websites and user actions on the website, visitor numbers and data such as countries being visited by. Google Analytics may capture your IP address, but no other personal information is captured by Google Analytics. We also have New Relic tracking our site. Please refer to [Google Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/privacy.html "Google Privacy Policy") for further information.

MailChimp  
For delivery of email updates and newsletters. They store your name and email address for the purposes of delivering such communications that you have given your consent to, along with any other information you have given them. Please refer to [Mailchimp Privacy Policy](http://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/ "MailChimp Privacy Policy") for further information.

Inlinkz  
We use Inlinkz to provide the opportunity to share our weekly giveaway and book link up. When you use Inlinkz to share your promotions, you voluntarily submit information such as your name and email address to the website which can only been seen by the account hosts and Inlinkz. Inlinkz will collect certain information about you and the device with which you access the website. Please refer to [Inlinkz Privacy Policy](http://www.inlinkz.com/new/privacy.php) for further information.

Rafflecopter  
We use Rafflecopter to provide the opportunity to share our book tour giveaways to you and to be able to share this over a number of blogs.  When you use Rafflecopter to enter our tour giveaways, you voluntarily submit information such as your name, email address and social media information etc which can only been seen by the account hosts and Rafflecopter.  Rafflecopter will capture your IP address, devices used and for more information please refer to [Rafflecopter Privacy Policy](https://www.rafflecopter.com/privacy-policy).

Social Media networks  
For automatically viewing our website information across social media networks that you have given consent to, along with any other information you have given them, for example: Facebook, Twitter, Google+,  Pinterest, Bloglovin, LinkedIn, StumbleUpon, Networked Blogs, LinkWithin. Please refer to their own privacy policies for further information listed below.

Advertising Tracking  
Google Adsense, Double Click, Add This, Blue Kai, Adknowledge, Scorecard Research Beacon, Content.Ad, Twitter Advertising, and Facebook Custom Audience, currently track our website usage, visitor numbers and advertising statistics. Please refer to their own privacy policies for further information.

At this time, your personal information is not shared with any other third-party applications.  
This list may be amended from time to time in the website’s sole discretion. Except when required by law, we will not sell, distribute, or reveal your email addresses or other personal information without your consent.

**Anonymous data:**  
From time to time, we may use anonymous data, which does not identify you alone, or when combined with data from other parties. This type of anonymous data may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. Examples of this anonymous data may include analytics or information collected from cookies.

**How your data is used:**

We may use the information collected in the following ways:

  * To operate and maintain the Website;
  * To send you promotional information, such as newsletters. Each email promotion will provide information on how to opt-out of future mailings;
  * To send you administrative communications, such as administrative emails, confirmation emails, technical notices, updates on policies, or security alerts;
  * To respond to your comments or inquiries;
  * To provide you with user support;
  * To track and measure advertising and usage on the Website;
  * To protect, investigate, and deter against unauthorized or illegal activity.

If, as determined by us, the lawful basis upon which we process your personal information changes, we will notify you about the change and any new lawful basis to be used if required.

**_Your individual rights_**

Under the GDPR your rights are as follows. You can read more about your rights in details here;  
<https://www.eugdpr.org/>

Opt-out – You may opt-out of future email communications by following the unsubscribe links in our emails. You may also notify us at beckvalleybooks@gmail.com to be removed from our mailing list.

Access – You may access the personal information we have about you by submitting a request to beckvalleybooks@gmail.com.

Amend – You may amend or update your personal information by following the update profile links in our emails or by contacting us at beckvalleybooks@gmail.com.

Forget – In certain situations, you may request that we erase or forget your personal data. To do so, please submit a request to beckvalleybooks@gmail.com.

Please note that we may need to retain certain information for record keeping purposes or to complete transactions, or when required by law. We handle subject access requests in accordance with the GDPR regulations.

**Internet cookies**  
We use cookies on this website to provide you with a better user experience. We do this by placing a small text file on your device / computer hard drive to track how you use the website, to record or log whether you have seen particular messages that we display, to keep you logged into the website where applicable, to display relevant adverts or content, referred you to a third party website, to be able to respond to your comments.

Some cookies are required to enjoy and use the full functionality of this website.

We use a cookie control system which allows you to accept the use of cookies, and control which cookies are saved to your device / computer. Some cookies will be saved for specific time periods, where others may last indefinitely. Your web browser should provide you with the controls to manage and delete cookies from your device, please see your web browser options.

**Sponsored links, affiliate tracking & commissions**  
Our website may contain adverts, sponsored and affiliate links on some pages. These are typically served through advertising partners such as; Google Adsense, eBay Partner Network, Amazon Affiliates, Groupon, or are self served through our own means. We only use trusted advertising partners who each have high standards of user privacy and security. However we do not control the actual adverts seen / displayed by our advertising partners.

Clickable sponsored or affiliate links may be displayed as a website URL like this; [www.beckvalleybooks.blogspot.com](http://www.beckvalleybooks.blogspot.com/) or as a titled text link like this: [Beck Valley Books](http://www.beckvalleybooks.blogspot.com/).

Clicking on any adverts, sponsored or affiliate links may track your actions by using a cookie saved to your device. You can read more about cookies on this website above. Your actions are usually recorded as a referral from our website by this cookie. In most cases we earn a very small commission from the advertiser or advertising partner, at no cost to you, whether you make a purchase on their website or not.

We use advertising partners in these ways to help generate an income from the website, which allows us to continue our work and provide you with the best overall experience and valued information.

If you have any concerns about this we suggest you do not click on any adverts, sponsored or affiliate links found throughout the website.

**Email marketing messages & subscription**  
Under the GDPR we use the consent lawful basis for anyone subscribing to our newsletter or marketing mailing list. We only collect certain data about you, as detailed in the "Processing of your personal data" above. Any email marketing messages we send are done so through an EMS, email marketing service provider. An EMS is a third party service provider of software / applications that allows marketers to send out email marketing campaigns to a list of users.

Email marketing messages that we send may contain tracking beacons / tracked clickable links or similar server technologies in order to track subscriber activity within email marketing messages. Where used, such marketing messages may record a range of data such as; times, dates, I.P addresses, opens, clicks, forwards, geographic and demographic data. Such data, within its limitations will show the activity each subscriber made for that email campaign.

Any email marketing messages we send are in accordance with the GDPR and the PECR. We provide you with an easy method to withdraw your consent (unsubscribe) or manage your preferences / the information we hold about you at any time. See any marketing messages for instructions on how to unsubscribe or manage your preferences, you can also unsubscribe from all MailChimp lists, by following this link, otherwise contact myself beckvalleybooks@gmail.com or the EMS provider.

Our EMS provider is; Mailchimp. 

**Childrens Information**  
The Website does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 16. If a parent or guardian believes that the website has personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 16 in its database, please contact us immediately at beckvalleybooks@gmail.com and we will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records. 

**Security**  
The security of your Personal Information is important to us, but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

**Transparent Privacy Explanations**  
We have provided some further explanations about user privacy and the way we use this website to help promote a transparent and honest user privacy methodology.

You can contact me at beckvalleybooks@gmail.com if you require any further information.

####  Resources & further information

Privacy Notice Policy Base: v.4.0 May 2018
